We celebrate the Govardhan Puja and Gopuja -
我们庆祝 Govardhan Puja（荣耀Govardhan 的节日）
the Worship of the Cows.
和Gopuja(崇拜奶牛的节日）
We know, on Srila Gurudev’s veranda...
我们知道在 Shrila Gurudev's( Govinda maharaj )的阳台上
He is sitting there.
他坐在那儿
If anyone will walk in before him
如果有人从他面前经过
with a bag or something
提着包或者拿着东西
whatever it might be,
不管是什么
he has to know what's inside it.
他要知道里面装的是什么
You cannot just walk by him...
你不可能只是从他面前经过......
He'll stare... You know...
他会盯着看... 你懂的...
He'll wanna know!
他渴望了解！
So, those who are his permanent servitors,
所以，那些在他身边服务了很久的人
his veranda servitors like Bhakti Lalita,
像是Bhakti Lalita
she would just show him all of her stuff
她需要把自己携带的所有东西给他看
without him asking,
即使他没有问
knowing that he wanted to see it.
她知道哪些是他想知道的
So, one of the things that,
所以，是这样一件事
there is a refrigerator
有一个冰箱
that she used and some others.
是她和其他人一起使用的
So, she would get the... her,
每当她到那里
how do you say it, the...
怎么讲呢
say, whatever she was eating for that day,
这么说吧，无论那天她吃的是什么
and have to walk in front of Gurudev.
如果，她需要从Gurudev面前经过
So, she would just turn and show him,
她要转向他
like just present it to him and he'd look.
给他看
Especially he had some interest in,
特别是当他颇有兴趣的时候
extraordinary interest in different types of food.
尤其对不同风格的食物
So, she showed him one day
正因如此，有一天她展示给他
and there is like different types of
一些不同的
lettuce, and celery, and green things and like that...
像是ladhus , 芹菜 ,绿叶菜等等
And Gurudev looked down like this and he said:
Gurudev像这样 注视着说：
“I can see that your Lord is Krishna”,
“我能看出krishna是你的至尊主”
like that, and then just...
然后
And she looked at me like...
她这样看着
"What's that?"
那是什么？
He said: “I can see your Lord is Krishna”.
Gurudev说：“ 我能从中看出Krishna是你的至尊主”
And he looked to me to see if I caught what he said.
然后他看着我，希望我能明白他的意思
And then I started smiling and laughing...
接着，我开始会意并大笑起来
And what he meant was, who is Krishna?
那意味着Krishna 是谁？
We just celebrated Govardhan Puja,
我们刚刚庆祝了Govardhan Puja
Gava Indra, Govinda - the Lord of the Cows.
天帝Indra, Govinda -  - 奶牛的保护者
So, he is saying:
因此他说：
”When I look at what you are about to eat,
“当我看到你们吃些什么
it looks like cow food to me”.
对我来讲就像母牛的食物”
But to say that, that would be insulting...
但是也许这么说很无礼...
So what did he say?
他怎么说的?
“I can see that your Lord is Krishna”.
“我能看见你的至尊主是Krishna”